JENNIE ROGNESS

1755 Drexel St., Dearborn, Mich. 48128 815-666-3768 | jrogness262@gmail.com

About me

I'm a designer who can brainstorm, research, write, edit as well as execute attractive designs. Organizing information into a visual is my specialty. Whether it's a graphic, brochure, magazine spread or social media image, I like the challenge of creating an easy-to-understand design.

Portfolio

COROFLOT.COM/JROGNESS

Skills

PLATFORMS

Macintosh and PC

SOFTWARE

Expert knowledge:

Adobe Creative Suite

- Photoshop
- InDesign
- Illustrator

Quark XPress

Macromedia Freehand

Microsoft Word

CCI publishing software

Saxotech publishing software

Working knowledge:

HTML

CSS

Microsoft Excel

Microsoft Powerpoint

Adobe Bridge

Sketch

Invision

KNOWLEDGE

AP Style

Compliance

Editing

Image Editing

Printing Processes

Professional experience

ART DIRECTOR

BNP Media, Troy, Mlch.

AUGUST 2017 TO PRESENT

Responsibilities: Design monthly *SDM* Magazine; Hire freelance photographers for cover shoots; Art direct cover shoots; Create print and digital marketing materials such as sell sheets, ads, email communications

TYPESETTER-CONTRACT

APRIL 2017 TO AUGUST 2017

Hayden-McNeil, Plymouth, Mich.

Responsibilities: Format textbooks; Make author corrections; Create print-ready pdfs

SENIOR GRAPHIC DESIGNER

APRIL 2014 TO JANUARY 2017

Catholic Order of Foresters, Naperville, Ill.

Responsibilities: Design quarterly magazine Catholic Forester; Create corporate advertising and marketing collateral, including direct mail letters, fliers, postcards, wall and standalone banners, email blasts, forms, logos, etc.; Photo editing

SPECIAL SECTIONS DESIGNER

FEBRUARY 2013 TO APRIL 2014

Gatehouse Media, Oakbrook Terrace, Ill.

Responsibilities: Design tabloid, broadsheet and magazine sections for members of Gatehouse Media; Design content pages for More Content Now news service; Convert and upload InDesign and Quark documents to More Content Now news service website; Export final pages to news sites; Create graphics and/or illustrations for More Content Now news service; Create ads and prototype websites for the Gatehouse online division

ASSISTANT DESIGN EDITOR

MAY 2010 TO OCTOBER 2012

The Journal Gazette, Fort Wayne, Ind.

Responsibilities: Delegate projects and daily work to design staff; Maintain publication style; Help train staff on current or new technology; Design section fronts, special sections and inside pages; Photo editing: including photo selection from local and wire news services, color correction, illustration; Research and create information graphics; Create marketing materials such as advertisements or static web banners to promote various special sections, unique content and the publication

GRAPHIC ARTIST/DESIGNER

SEPTEMBER 2001 TO MAY 2010

The Journal Gazette, Fort Wayne, Ind.

Responsibilities: Design section fronts, special sections and inside pages; Photo editing: including photo selection from local and wire news services, color correction, illustration; Research and create information graphics

Education

BALL STATE UNIVERSITY

FALL 1997 TO SUMMER 2001

Muncie. Ind.

Bachelor of Science degree in Journalism Graphics; Geography minor

GENERAL ASSEMBLY

2017

Online HTML, CSS & Web Design Circuit User Experience Design Circuit